Finding Aid for the Yuji Ichioka Papers LSC.0242
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Materials
  - Other Issei Individuals
    - Nakamura Gongoro biography (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Nakazawa Ken materials (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Picture Brides and Immigrant Women
    - Clippings and notes of Nichibei Shimbun and Shin Sekai articles, relating to failed marriages, etc (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to Issei women and picture marriage, 1910-1915 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to Issei women and picture marriage, 1916-1917, 1919- 1923 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Taihoku Nippo clippings and notes relating to Issei women and their problems, 1911- 1915 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Copies of Shin Sekai reports on picture brides at Angel Island, April-May 1920 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Shin Sekai editorials criticizing Tokyo's decision to end picture marriage migration, 1919 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Shin Sekai editorials criticizing Tokyo's decision to end picture marriage migration, 1919 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Rafu Shimpo editorials criticizing Tokyo's decision to end picture marriage migration, 1919 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Materials pertaining to controversy over the ban on picture marriage migration, 1919- 1920 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Notes and clippings of American newspapers relating to Issei's picture marriage practice, 1913, 1919 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - U.S. government position on the admission of Japanese picture brides (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Photocopy of Zaibei Nihonjinkai ??????, Shin Tobei fujin no shiori ??????????A new guide for America- bound women?; and newspaper clippings relating to picture brides, 1916, 1919 (Box 155, Folder 10)
      (See also Box 61, Folders 1-4.)
  - Prostitutes and "Undesirables"
    - Consular reports on Japanese prostitutes in the Pacific Coast states, 1889- 1896 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Vancouver consul's dispatches relating to local Japanese prostitutes, 1890- 1891 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Papers pertaining to Japanese prostitutes in the Pacific Coast states, 1897- 1898 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to Japanese prostitutes, 1900, 1908-1910 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Clippings of American newspapers relating to Japanese prostitutes and itinerant laborers, 1890-1899 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - English-language magazine and newspaper articles on labor migration from Japan, 1889- 1913 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Papers pertaining to Nishimura Ekiu v. U.S., 1891 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Papers pertaining to "Ameyuki-san," especially Yamada Waka (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Ministry dispatches regarding Issei gamblers and other criminal elements in Honolulu, 1900 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to crimes and social problems in Japanese immigrant society, 1908- 1910 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Clippings of English language newspapers relating to Japanese laborers and prostitutes, 1895-1899, (Oversize) (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Redress
    - Aiko and Jack Herzig research papers relating to the CWRIC (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Aiko and Jack Herzig papers relating to Karl Bendetsen and other CWRIC research matters (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - CWRIC testimonies, 1981 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - CWRIC testimonies, printed in Amerasia Journal (1981) (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Materials pertaining to the National Council for Japanese American Redress, 1986- 1988 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Legal documents relating to Gordon Hirabayashi Coram Nobis case, 1985-1986 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Legal documents relating to William Hohri, et al. class action law suit, 1985- 1986 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Testimonies for H.R. 442 redress bill, 1986 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Asianweek special reports, April 7-28, 1989 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous materials relating to wartime internment, Nisei military service and camp reunions (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to Mike Masaoka and his wartime role, 1983, 1987 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Deborah K. Lim, "The Lim Report" (1990), 2 versions (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Francis Y. Sogi and Yeichi Kuwayama, "Japanese Americans Disunited" (2000) (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Religion
    - Beikoku Bukkyo, vol. 11, no. 1, 4, 7 (1910) (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Beikoku Bukkyo, vol. 11, no. 11 (1910); vol. 12, no. 1, 2 (1911) (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Beikoku Bukkyo, vol. 12, no. 3-5 (1911) (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Beikoku Bukkyo, vol. 12, no. 6, 9 (1911); vol. 13, no. 10, 12 (1912) (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Beikoku Bukkyo, vol. 14, no. 1-3 (1913) (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Beikoku Bukkyo, vol. 14, no. 4-6, 8 (1913) (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Beikoku Bukkyo clippings, 1910-1914 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Sacramento Nishi Hongwanji Betsuin, "Kakocho" (1900-1902) (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Zaibei Nihonjin Choro Kyokai Rekishi (1912) (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Shin Tenchi, vol. 1, no. 2-5 (1910); vol. 2, no. 1-2, 4-5 (1911) (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Research Notebooks
    - Notebooks, "I-III" (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks, "IV-VI" (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks, "VII-IX" (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Research notebooks on Japanese diplomatic papers and World War II Japanese newspapers., 1999 (Box 149, Folder 10)
      (See also Box 36, Folders 4-7.)
  - Research Notes
    - Checklists of Japanese Immigrant Newspaper Articles (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Social Adaptation and Racial Exclusion
    - Japanese newspaper clippings relating to "permanent settlement and assimilation," 1908-1923 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Nichibei Shimbun research notes relating to social adaptation and exclusion, 1912- 1925 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to anti-Japanese agitation and exclusion, 1908- 1913 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to anti-Japanese agitation and exclusion, 1914-1917, 1919 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to anti-Japanese agitation and exclusion, 1920, 1922 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to Issei naturalization and the Ozawa test case, 1906- 1923 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Materials pertaining to Issei naturalization and the Ozawa test case (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Ozawa Takao correspondence file, 1917-1921 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Legal papers relating to the Ozawa naturalization test case (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Research notes and biographical data relating to Ozawa Takao (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Japanese Association of North America correspondence file relating to the Ozawa test case, 1917-1919 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Japanese immigrant newspaper editorials relating to the 1924 Immigration Act (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Materials relating to the impact of the 1924 Immigration Act on Issei (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Materials relating to the 1921 Turlock incident (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Materials relating to the 1934 Arizona incident (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Social Scientists in Internment Camps
    - Edward Barnhart, "JERS Catalog of Material in the General Library" (1958) (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Papers relating to JERS and WRA community analysts, 1942-1943 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Frank Miyamoto's reports, 1943-1944 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Richard Nishimoto's reports, 1943-1944, 1952-1953 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - James Sakoda's reports, 1942-1943 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Tamotsu Shibutani's reports, 1942-1946 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Tamotsu Shibutani's reports, 2 items (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Edward Spicer's correspondence with Dorothy Swaine Thomas, 1943 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Tamie Tsuchiyama's reports, 1943-1944 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Published works by JERS affiliated scholars (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Papers relating to Morton Grodzin affair, 1945-1949 (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Togo Tanaka file on William T. Couch and the Grodzin affair (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Registry of Edward H. Spicer Papers (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Papers relating to James H. Barnett and G. Gordon Brown, 1943-1946 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Papers relating to John De Young, 1943-1945 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to John Embree, 1942-1944 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Papers relating to David and Katherine French, 1943-1945; and Philip Glick, 1945 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Papers relating to Asael Hansen, 1944-1946 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to Solon Kimbell, Weston La Barre, and Katherine Luomala, 1943- 1946 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Papers relating to Forrest La Violette, 1943-1944 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Papers relating to Edgar McVoy, 1943 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Papers relating to Dillon Myer, 1943-1946 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Papers relating to Dillon Myer, 1943-1946 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Papers relating to Morris Opler and Marvin Opler, 1943-1946 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Paper relating to John Provinse, 1943-1945 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Papers relating to John Rademaker, 1943-1945 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to Rachel Sady and Elmer Smith, 1944-1946 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Papers relating to Edward Spicer, 1943-1945 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Papers relating to Frank Sweetster, 1943, and M. Tozier, 1945-1946 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to Harold Ickes, 1943-1946 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous papers relating to the WRA Community Analysis Section, 1942- 1946 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Letters from Japanese Americans to Edward Spicer, 1943-1945 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Writings of John Embree and Edward Spicer relating to the WRA Community Analysis Section (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Writings of WRA Community Analysts (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Peter Suzuki's essays on camp social scientists, 1980-1993 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Studies of social science research in internment camps (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Tachibana Espionage Incident
    - FBI reports on Furusawa Sachiko and Furusawa Takashi (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - FBI reports on Furusawa Sachiko and Furusawa Takashi (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - INS enemy alien case file on Furusawa Sachiko (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Biographical materials relating to Furusawa Takashi and Furusawa Sachiko (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Papers pertaining to "Fujin Kogun Imonshi," April-May 1938 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Materials pertaining to Kono Toraichi (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to the Tachibana espionage incident and local Japanese reactions, 1941 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Al Blake, "Me, Jap Agent--For Uncle Sam" (1942) (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - "Umi to Sora" (March 1941) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Sanemitsu Yuzuru, Maboroshi no Saigo Tsucho (1995) (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Yuji Ichioka research correspondence (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous materials (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - FBI report on Nippon Kaigun Kyokai, August 26, 1941, pp. 1-151 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - FBI report on Nippon Kaigun Kyokai, August 26, 1941, pp. 152-307 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Various intelligence reports on Nippon Kaigun Kyokai, 1941-1946 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Justice Department files on members of Nippon Kaigun Kyokai, 1943-1944 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - FBI reports on Tachibana Itaru and Okada Sadatomo (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - FBI and ONI reports on alleged Japanese espionage, 1941 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Government Reports
    - Reports of Superintendent (Commissioner-General) of Immigration, 1892-1929 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - California Superintendent of Banks Annual Reports, 1905-1925 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous reports on Japanese immigration and immigrant activities, 1901- 1911 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous reports on Japanese immigration and immigrant activities, 1920- 1942 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Hawaii Issei
    - Sôga Yasutarô ????? correspondence., 1911, 1917, 1919 (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings by Sôga Yasutarô ????? relating to the Korean independence movement and other matters., Undated. (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - Hawai Dôshikai????? bylaws, newsletters, and membership roster., 1945-1946 (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Hawai Dôshikai????? correspondence and photos., 1945-1946 (Box 155, Folder 4)
  - Issei Individual File
    - Materials relating Abiko KyutarÔ ?????? and the operation of Nichibei Shimbun ????., Undated. (Box 153, Folder 5)
      (See also Box 37, Folder 3.)
    - Materials pertaining to Oka Shieki ??? and Oka Naoki ???., Undated. (Box 153, Folder 6)
  - Japanese American Communists
    - Japanese American communists of the 1930s, including USSR KGB files., Undated. (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - Japanese American communists of the 1930s, including Joe Koide, Nao Nishi, Nozaka Sanzô ????, and other California Issei., Undated. (Box 155, Folder 9)
  - Japanese American Internment
    - Hatchimonji ??? family internment papers., Undated. (Box 154, Folder 8)
      (See also Boxes 92-93.)
    - Santafe Jihô ???????, "Santafe Nihonjin Shûyôjo jinmeiroku" ???????????????? [Directory of Japanese detainees at the Santa Fe Internment Camp]., November 1943 (Box 154, Folder 9)
    - Photocopies of Yamanouchi Teijirô ?????? correspondence with his family members. (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous internment-related materials., Undated. (Box 154, Folder 11)
      (See also Box 94.)
    - Original issues of Trek, December 1942, Feb. 1943, June 1943; and All Aboard, Spring 1944., Undated. (Box 154, Folder 12)
  - Local Community Histories
    - Newspaper clippings regarding early histories of Japanese communities in Fresno, Salinas, Watsonville, Terminal Island, and southern California., 1909-1918, 1976 (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - Nisei Individual File
    - Photos and slides relating to Buddy Kazumaro Uno., Undated. (Box 148, Folder 6)
      (See also Boxes 81-83.)
    - Miscellaneous materials on individual Nisei., Undated. (Box 148, Folder 7)
  - Research Aids
    - "A Select Bibliography of Japanese-Americans During the Second World War." Compiled by Yuji Ichioka for personal use., 1994, 1996 (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - "A Select Bibliography of Japanese-Americans During the Second World War." Compiled by Yuji Ichioka for personal use., 1997, 1999 (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Bibliographic materials on UCLA's library holdings and lists of microfilms relating to Japanese American history., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Information regarding microfilms of Japanese diplomatic papers., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographies of Emigration-related materials at Ryûkyû University ????and Takushoku Universaity ????., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Bibliographies of emigration-related materials at the National Diet Library of Japan ?????., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Bibliography of the Yamamoto Collection at the National Diet Library of Japan ?????., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - List of Japanese TV programs and film productions relating to overseas Japanese and emigrants., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - "Directory of Organizations Dealing with Asian-Pacific Immigrants and Refugees and Selected Bibliography on Asian- Pacific Immigration History.", 1980 (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Chronologies and references on prewar Japanese American history. Compiled by Yuji Ichioka., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Glossary of Japanese military terms., Undated. (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Centro de Estudos Nipo-Brasileiros, ed., "Japanese and Their Descendants in Brazil: An Annotated Bibliography." Saõ Paulo, Brazil., 1967 (Box 155, Folder 11)
  - Tachibana Espionage Incident
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) reports and photos relating to Furusawa Sachiko ???? and Furusawa Takashi ???., 1942-1943 (Box 150, Folder 1)
      (See also Box 74, Folder 8.)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) reports on Nippon Kaigun Kyôkai ?????? ?Japan Navy Association? and Sakurakai ?? ?Cherry Association?., September 1939-August 1940 (Box 150, Folder 2)
      (See also Box 76, Folders 1-3.)
    - FBI reports on Nippon Kaigun Kyôkai ?????? ?Japan Navy Association? and Sakurakai ?? ?Cherry Association?., August 26, 1941 (Box 150, Folder 3)
      (See also Box 76, Folders 1-2 for the same copy.)
    - FBI reports on Nippon Kaigun Kyôkai ?????? ?Japan Navy Association? and Sakurakai ?? ?Cherry Association?., September 1941-February 1943 (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - FBI reports on Nippon Kaigun Kyôkai ?????? ?Japan Navy Association? and Sakurakai ?? ?Cherry Association?., November 1942-May 1951 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - FBI reports on "Toraichi Kono" ???? ?Kôno Toraichi?., July 1940-May 1941 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      (See also Box 75, Folder 2.)
    - FBI reports on "Toraichi Kono" ???? ?Kôno Toraichi?., May 1941-June 1941 (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - FBI reports on "Toraichi Kono" ???? ?Kôno Toraichi?., June 1941-September 1942 (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - FBI reports on "Toraichi Kono" ???? ?Kôno Toraichi?, including a cross-reference file., September 1942-1955 (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - World War II
    - Photocopies of Japanese-language U.S. propaganda leaflets for the Battle of Okinawa., Late 1944 (Box 152, Folder 2)
- Teaching Materials
  - Community Lectures
    - Japanese American History (1979, 1981, 1983, 1985-1986, 1988) (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Community lecture drafts, ca. 1970s-1980s (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Community lecture drafts, ca. 1970s-1980s (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Community lecture drafts, ca. 1970s-1980s (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - "Japanese-Americans and U.S.-Japan Relations: A Summary of Prewar Times," draft of lecture for the JACL International Relations Committee., February 6. 1972 (Box 152, Folder 3)
      (See also Box 145, Folder 2.)
    - "Japanese Associations," lecture draft., ca. 1970s. (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - "Approaches to Immigration History"; and "Gambling," lecture drafts., ca. 1970s. (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - "Who Are We?: A Recurring Question and Vexation Problem for Japanese Americans," outline and notes for a public lecture sponsored by the Southern California Adult Buddhist Association. Santa Monica., January 25, 1985 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - UCLA course materials relating to "Japanese-American History," Asian American Studies 130D., 1998, 2001 (Box 152, Folder 7)
      (See also Box 105, Folders 1-2.)
    - UCLA course materials relating to "The Wartime Internment of Japanese Americans," Asian American Studies 197A., 1995, 1997, 1998 (Box 152, Folder 8)
      (See also Box 106, Folders 1-2.)
    - UCLA course materials relating to "The Wartime Internment of Japanese Americans," Asian American Studies 197A., 1999 (Box 152, Folder 9)
  - Course Materials
    - History 198 (1970); and History 192 (1979) (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - CED 106 (1972, 1975-1976); History 197X (1976-1977); History 198T (1980); and Asian American Studies 197A (1981) (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Asian American Studies 197C (1983-1985); Asian American Studies 197B (1986-1987); and Asian American Studies 197A (1988-1989) (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Asian American Studies 195D (1989-1994) (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Asian American Studies 130D (1995, 1997-2001) (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Handouts for "Japanese-American History" courses (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Asian American Studies 297 (1980): "Seminar on Nisei" (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Papers submitted for "Seminar on Nisei" (1981) (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Papers submitted for "Seminar on Nisei" (1981) (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Papers submitted for "Seminar on Nisei" (1981) (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Asian American Studies 297 (1983, 1985-1989, 1991): Nisei and internment (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Asian American Studies 197A (1992-1995) (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Asian American Studies 197A (1996-1997, 2000) (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - University of Tokyo course on internment, Week 1-4 (1999-2000) (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - University of Tokyo course on internment, Week 5-7 (1999-2000) (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - University of Tokyo course on internment, Week 8-11 (1999-2000) (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - University of Tokyo course on internment, Week 12-16 (1999-2000) (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - University of Tokyo course on "Asians in Contemporary America" (1999-2000) (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - UCLA course materials relating to "Japanese-American History," Asian American Studies 130D., 1998, 2001 (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - UCLA course materials relating to "The Wartime Internment of Japanese Americans," Asian American Studies 197A., 1995, 1997, 1998 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - UCLA course materials relating to "The Wartime Internment of Japanese Americans," Asian American Studies 197A., 1999 (Box 152, Folder 9)
- Archival Development
  - Japanese American Research Project
    - Papers relating to the development of UCLA Asian American collections, 1991-1992, 1996 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Papers relating to the acquisition of Abiko Family Papers, 1991-1992 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to an Abiko Family Papers project with Tsuda Women's College, 1990- 1992 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Papers relating to the acquisition of Akira Fujita Papers, 1995 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Papers relating to the acquisition of Togawa Akira Papers, 1993 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to the acquisition of Edison Uno Papers, 1984 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Papers relating to the acquisition of Karl G. Yoneda Papers, 1990 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Papers relating to the acquisition of miscellaneous personal papers (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Lists of Japanese American-related materials at the UCLA East Asian Library (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Korean American Research Project
    - Working file relating to the Korean American Research Project, 1991 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Working file relating to the Korean American Research Project, 1991-1992, 1995- 1997 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Working file relating to the Korean American Research Project, 1992 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Working file relating to the Korean American Research Project, 1992 (Box 109, Folder 3)
- Subject Files
  - Conference Presentations
    - Toyota Foundation international symposium, 1984 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - "Louis Adamic and the Question of Ethnicity", 1986 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - The Sixth Annual Meeting of the Association for Asian American Studies, 1989 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - The Fifth Convention of the Pan American Nikkei Association, 1989 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - "Documenting the Immigration Experience," 1990 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Organization of American Historians Annual Meeting, 1991 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - VIII COPANI Peru, 1995 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Society of American Archivists Annual Meeting, 1996 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - "Beyond Diaspora from the Global Perspectives Focusing on Asia Pacific," 1997 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - IX COPANI Mexico, 1999 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - "Pacific Diaspora," 1999 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - AHA-PCB 94th Annual Meeting, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Grant and Fellowship Proposals
    - Japan Foundation Research Fellowship, 1981 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Toyota Foundation Grant, 1983-1984 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Japan Society for the Promotion of Science Research Fellowship, 1996 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Miscellanies
    - Eiichiro Azuma's research relating to Walnut Grove (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Eiichiro Azuma's research relating to Walnut Grove (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - "California Japanese Survey," August 1957 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - "California Japanese Survey," August 1957 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - "California Japanese Survey," August 1957 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - "California Japanese Survey," August 1957 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Gordon Chang file, 1992-1996 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - "Disney's America" Conference, 1994 (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Papers relating to disputes between Kilsoo Haan and the Nippu Jiji, 1938-1941 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - "Filipinos"--Research notes (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Fukuda Yoshiaki autobiography project, 1989 (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - Futatsu no Sokoku controversy, 1984-1985 (Box 115, Folder 1)